{"Topic": "Governor Generals", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Who was the Governor-General of India during the launch of Civil Disobedience Movement?", "op1": "Lord Chelmsford", "op2": "Lord Reading", "op3": "Lord Irwin", "op4": "Lord Wavell", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Consider the following statements :", "op1": "1 only", "op2": "2 only", "op3": "Both 1 and 2", "op4": "Neither 1 nor 2", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "ch of the statements given above is/are correct?", "op1": "Lord Ripon", "op2": "Warren Hastings", "op3": "Lord Cornwallis", "op4": "William Bentinck", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "\u2018Sati\u2019 was abolished by", "op1": "Cornwallis", "op2": "Clive", "op3": "Hardinge", "op4": "Warren Hastings", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The Treaty of Sreerangapattam was between Tipu Sultan and", "op1": "Warren Hastings", "op2": "Curzon", "op3": "Canning", "op4": "Ripon", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Under whose administration did the Archaeological Survey of India start functioning?", "op1": "Bombay", "op2": "Madras", "op3": "Delhi", "op4": "Calcutta", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following universities was not established by Lord Dalhousie?", "op1": "Lord Cornwallis", "op2": "Lord Hastings", "op3": "Lord William Bentinck", "op4": "Lord Dalhousie", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who was the British Governor General in India in whose reign a part of Charter Act read like this, \"No native of India nor natural born subject of His Majesty, should be disabled from holding any place, office of employment by reason of his religion, place of birth, descent or colour. \"", "op1": "Lord Linlithgow", "op2": "Lord Ripon", "op3": "Lord Minto", "op4": "Lord Curzon", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The partition of Bengal in 1905 was effected by :", "op1": "Lord Linlithgow", "op2": "Lord Wavell", "op3": "Lord Mountbatten", "op4": "Lord Irwin", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who was the last British Viceroy of India?", "op1": "Lord Dalhousie - Doctrine of Lapse", "op2": "Lord Minto - Indian Councils Act, 1909", "op3": "Lord Wellesley - Subsidiary Alliance", "op4": "Lord Curzon - Vernacular Press Act, 1878", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following pairs is not correctly matched?", "op1": "Lord Wavell", "op2": "Lord Lytton", "op3": "Lord Irwin", "op4": "Lord Canning", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "With which of the following did Mahatma Gandhi sign a pact to suspend the Civil Disobedience Movement and take part in the Round Table Conference?", "op1": "Lord Cornwallis", "op2": "Lord Ripon", "op3": "Lord Canning", "op4": "Lord Dalhousie", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Indian  Railways and telegraph services were started during the reign of :", "op1": "William Bentinck", "op2": "Lord Cornwallis", "op3": "Lord Curzon", "op4": "Lord Dalhousie", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who among the following was associated with the Permanent Settlement of Bengal?", "op1": "William Bentinck", "op2": "Lord Cornwallis", "op3": "Lord Curzon", "op4": "Lord Dalhousie", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who among the following is known as the Maker of Modern India?", "op1": "Warren Hastings", "op2": "Lord Cornwallis", "op3": "Lord Wellesley", "op4": "Lord William Bentick", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who among the following Governor-Generals formed the Triple Alliance against Tipu Sultan?", "op1": "Lord Dufferin", "op2": "Lord Lytton", "op3": "Lord Ripon", "op4": "Lord Dalhousie"}, {"Question": "Dalhousie has been regarded as the maker of modern India because he brought about reforms and made a beginning in many fields. Which one among the following was not one of his schemes of reforms?", "op1": "Educational reforms", "op2": "Construction of railways and introduction of telegraphs and postal services", "op3": "Establishment of a public works department", "op4": "Factories Act to improve the condition of Indian Labour", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who among the following is known as the Father of Local Self Government in India?", "op1": "Lord Dalhousie", "op2": "Lord Ripon", "op3": "Lord Minto", "op4": "Lord Reading", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Under whose Governor Generalship was the hated Vernacular Press Act passed in 1878?", "op1": "Lord Canning", "op2": "Lord Ripon", "op3": "Lord Lytton", "op4": "Lord Minto", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Match List I with List II and select the correct answer using the code given below:", "op1": "A - 3; B - 1; C - 2", "op2": "A - 2; B - 1; C - 3", "op3": "A - 3; B - 2; C - 1", "op4": "A - 1; B - 2; C - 3", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Match List I with List II and select the correct answer using the code given below:", "op1": "A - 3; B - 4; C - 1; D - 2", "op2": "A - 2; B - 4; C - 1; D - 3", "op3": "A - 2; B - 1; C - 4; D - 3", "op4": "A - 3; B - 1; C - 4; D - 2", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the target of an assassination attempt in the Delhi conspiracy case headed by Rash Bihari Bose in 1911?", "op1": "Lord Chelmsford", "op2": "Lord Ripon", "op3": "Lord Hardinge", "op4": "Lord Minto", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Rowlatt Act which authorised the Government to detain people without trial for an indefinite period was passed during the tenure of -", "op1": "Lord Chelmsford", "op2": "Lord Irwin", "op3": "Lord Hardinge", "op4": "Lord Reading", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "When Gandhiji was imprisoned for the first time in India, the Governor General of India was -", "op1": "Lord Chelmsford", "op2": "Lord Irwin", "op3": "Lord Hardinge", "op4": "Lord Reading", "Answer": 2}]}